Believe it or not... He's the good guy.
Hellboy II: The Golden Army is a fantasy, action
film directed by Guillermo del Toro.
Hellboy, his pyrokinetic girlfriend, Liz, and aquatic empath, Abe Sapien, face their biggest
battle when an underworld elven prince plans to reclaim Earth for his magical kindred.
Tired of living in the shadow of humans, Prince Nuada tries to awaken an ancient force of killing
machines, the all-powerful Golden Army, to clear the way for fantasy creatures to roam free.
Only Hellboy can stop the dark prince and prevent humanity's annihilation.
Hellboy, played by Ron Perlman.
Liz Sherman, played by Selma Blair.
Abe Sapien / Chamberlain / Angel of Death, played by Doug Jones.
Johann Krauss / Bethmoora Goblin, played by John Alexander.
Johann Krauss (voice), played by Seth MacFarlane.
Prince Nuada, played by Luke Goss.
Hellboy II: The Golden Army is a 2008 American fantasy horror superhero film
based on the Dark Horse Comics character, created by Mike Mignola.
It is a sequel to Hellboy (2004) and is the second
live-action film in the franchise.
It was written and directed by Guillermo del Toro
from a story he co-wrote with Mignola.
Ron Perlman stars as Hellboy, alongside Selma Blair,
Doug Jones, Jeffrey Tambor, and John Hurt.
In the film, Hellboy and the Bureau of Paranormal Research and Defense must battle a
mythical prince who plans to reclaim the world for his magical kindred.
Hellboy II: The Golden Army was released in the United States on July 11, 2008, to generally positive reviews from
critics, with praise towards its fantasy atmosphere as well as Perlman and the other cast's acting performances.
It grossed $168.3 million against a production budget of $82.5–85 million.
The film received a nomination for Best Makeup at the 81st Academy Awards.
The franchise was rebooted in 2019, with a new film simply
titled Hellboy, and was released by Lionsgate.
Following the critical and commercial failure of the film, a second reboot was announced in 2023,
titled Hellboy: The Crooked Man which itself was a critical and commercial disappointment.
The film explores themes of rebellion, superhero,
auction, northern ireland, based on comic.
The tone is dark.